Now we're going to talk about what some things not to do that can create a lot of ill will and problems in relationships with regard to communication.
And this one's, this is a hard one.
This is a hard one to resist.
It is gossip.
And what is gossip?
Well, it's social talk that makes evaluations about another person when they're not there to defend themselves, basically.
But gossip actually does a lot of other things well.
It can create some very negative things which if you're in it; it might not seem negative, but to the outsider looking in, can be very negative.
Gossip can create an in group, the group that gossips together.
Can cause, can help regulate the behavior of an organization.
Thus, the climate of the workplace, the climate of the school classroom, the climate of any type of environment can be regulated by the people who gossip, and the energy that that gossip puts out.
Basically, the bottom line on gossip, is it is a negative thing that is very hard to repair.
And should be, no matter how difficult, avoided at all costs.
Just don't do it.
Just sacrifice not being in the in group.
Don't gossip.